hey guys rexin here withering waves is
launching or has already launched by the
time of this posting and I know a lot of
you are curious about how the characters
are played and what the combat is like
so that is the agenda of this video I
will go over each character and briefly
teach you how their Forte circuits AKA
their play style is done first of all
thanks to Kuro games for sponsoring this
video the footage that you see is from a
test server and does not represent the
final build so that's a disclaimer I
have to put it out there but the
character gameplay should still remain
mostly accurate it also as you know
since cbt2 was pretty short I have had
limited time and resources to play all
the characters so we will not go too in
depth on the optimal Combos and stuff
we'll keep it simple and I'll explain
them to the best of my abilities before
we begin let me quickly summarize the
combat system in withering waves so
combat controls are pretty standard with
the left click button you have your
basic attack combo chain doing it while
jumping with the space bar will also
result in a plch attack this consumes
stamina
holding basic attack will trigger heavy
attack and this also consumes stamina
next the resonance skill which is the
character's standard skill this is
mapped to the E Key by default and they
are generally cooldown based after that
there's also resonance Liberation which
is their signature move AKA ultimate
move mapped to the r key will'll just
simplify resonance skill and resonance
Liberation as the e and r Keys
respectively resonators can also equip
Echo for stats and bonus effects and the
topmost Echo that you equip will be
assigned to the echo skill command the q
key same thing they're also cool down
based right click is dodging and when
you activate this and successfully
dodging an incoming attack everything
will be momentarily
slowed dodging also has a minor delay if
you do it twice in a row so that's
something to take note of next is the T
key which is a shortcut for utility
Tools in this case I'll be using the
grapple now if you look at the bottom
center of the screen there's a ring
gauge and a horizontal gauge for every
character starting with the ring gauge
that is the conto energy this gauge
builds up as you do combat and once it's
filled the game will indicate that a
powerful character switch is ready what
this does is that it will trigger the
leaving character's outro skill and at
the same time the intro skill of the
next character while also dealing big
damage to the enemy's vibration strength
gauge aka the Stagger gauge of Elites
and bosses you can take your time to
check the outro and intro skill of each
character in the game and this is basic
basically how team composition decisions
are made based on the outro skills of
the characters as most of them come with
Buffs that benefit the next character
last but not least the Forte circuit
gauge in other words the core passive of
each character and what makes them
unique in their kit and this is what
I'll be mainly talking about in this
video so let us begin starting with our
main character
Rover okay I'll keep it brief as this is
just a guideline to get you started on
the game you can read the rest of the
tool tips in game at your own time so
beginning with Rover you can see that
that he has a gauge here and a hint to
know how a character is played is to
look at this over here so for Rover it
shows e that means every time you press
e as long as there's half a gauge
available his resonate attack will be
enhanced so I'll show you when I press e
it'll look like
this and there is a followup to this so
you press e and then you press basic
attack again on the enhanced resonant
attack so e
basic that's it the gauge will charge on
its own when you battle and this is what
the basic e looks like without any
enhancement like that just a simple
slash and then for his basic attack when
you spam basic attack four times in a
row it looks like
this like that however if you pause on
the third combo wait a bit and then
press basic attack after the delay 1 2
three pause basic like that so 1 2 3
pause basic that's it for Rover and then
for his ultimate it's just a front AOE
burst it's a really large AOE so it's
really good for clearing mops so let me
start crownless and show you some
demonstration if you see a golden ring
like that that's the Parry simply just
press attack or skill against it once
the two circles align and then Parry
will do a lot of damage to their
vibration gauge so vibration gauge is
that white gauge at the top once it goes
empty the boss will go into a down stair
so let's see what happens normal attack
also reduces the vibration gauge
switching also reduces it by a lot so
let me switch YY in see one whole Chun
gone and there we go so this is another
basic for combat the Stagger so once
enemies uh go into zero vibration they
go into a down state and then you see
the yellow gauge uh gradually go down
and then they'll recover like that and
then it resets and then you do it again
as for yyang it's really simple as well
basic attack combo looks like this
normal and then for her heavy
attack she has a followup so it's this
stab and then if you press basic attack
after it there's a followup to it so for
her gauge as you can see it's broken
down into three parts she gets one part
every time she does either a fourth
combo or her e skill or that followup
has attack or a Dodge counter so lots of
sources I can't demonstrate it right now
because she needs to be in combat to get
a gauge but I'll explain her e and r
skill for E skill it's simple it's a
it's a mini gter AOE like that that's
all you need to know and then for R
skill even bigger G big
vacuum and then she has eye frame during
during
this so let me show you a core passive
so three
gauges just press and hold basic and
press basic
again that is a core
passive so let me do it one more
time okay press and hold basic press
again she can also activate this in the
in
midair so let me demonst straight like
that just like that okay for tusia it's
really simple she has two charges to her
e so if you tap e it'll look like this
and you can control the direction of her
slide doing this will give her 25 points
to her gauge and as you can see I
already have it maxed out at 60 so what
this gauge does is if you hold e she
will expand her gauge and go into a
shooting
frenzy and then after 30 bullets are
spent you can press basic attack for a
really huge nuke attack ho
e and then there's a marker below and
now She Glows left click so that's the
big attack one thing to note about guns
is that you can go into manual aiming by
pressing G like this she'll also charge
up her weapon that's the charge shot you
can also do this by holding left click
without going into full manual
aiming and one thing to not is that
pistols cannot Parry so look look at
this you got to dodge them it does
nothing all right so let's do her e hold
e and then left click when it She
Glows like that all right next up b b is
really simple to use four parts to
engage each part is gained by performing
a basic attack and then you consume them
all either using e or whole basic attack
which is a heavy attack so if I press
e those four Stacks will turn into regen
if you press and whole basic attack into
a heavy
attack Yan will be constantly attacking
the enemy and you can control the
direction it goes consume stamina as you
can see and then you can just release
when you're done as for her attacks it's
kind of difficult to Parry with so
usually I would just do a jump attack
like that because it sends yotan to the
boss like that and every time you dodge
it calls it back to
her
again jump attack that's the best way to
Parry in my experience so I have four
Stacks I can consume them all using
e normal attack again four stacks and
then you can also hold basic attack you
can just hold the bit and release and
then she spends all the stacks and
that's it for her ultimate it's also a
heal and then uh regenerative heal over
time as long as it hits the
enemy like that pulsing
heal and that's how you play bit for
sanwa it's really simple press and hold
basic attack and you can see at the
bottom of the gauge the ticker moves
from left to right all you need to do is
release it as it's in the blue field
here like
that and then she'll do her enhanced
charge
attack she places an ice with her e
skill and then when you do the same
charge attack she'll shatter it and you
can also notice that the window is also
bigger after doing e so you shatter it
again like that
all right same thing for ultimate she
places an ice so you can use ultimate
and then you use your e and then press
and hole and shatter them all that's how
you play
sanwa you can also do this if you're
really good at Rhythm games constantly
pressing in hole and releasing it on the
blue and lastly her intro attack she
places an ice like that so intro ice e
ice Ultimate Ice three ice and then you
shatter them all three together
and that's how you play sanoa moving on
to the next character okay for taoi
first of all it's all about using her e
skill and it'll give her three charges
of these and if she takes damage it'll
be converted into one part of the gauge
or when it expires then all of them will
be turned into the gauge and I'll
explain what the gauge does in the next
section before I begin combat you can
press and hold basic attack and she'll
go into a blocking stance and any attack
that she takes she'll counter it and
that's when you press basic attack
constantly and she will use up her gauge
for an enhanced combo and then you rinse
and repeat you press e again and convert
it into gauge and then Parry attack
again so now that I have a full gauge
I'll show you what I mean I will block
the first
attack and then just press left click
this is the enhanced combo like that and
then it turns into Shield so now I press
e
again so I have three of these if I take
hit it turns into a gauge
can also block
it gauge so I got hit again so that's
three gauges
again you can also wait for this to
expire and she'll go into a Parry combo
anyway like
that so tldr either she takes damage or
when the shield expires so it's going to
expire soon see three gauges
again block left click all the
way there we go e
again for e skill also transfer to the
next character so they get defense up
with it and for her intro when she comes
into battle with her intro attack she
goes straight into the Parry combo with
a full gauge so you can just constantly
press basic attack once she enters the
field like that just left click all the
way it's the enhanced combo
see and that's how you play tchi next
character okay so for alto how to
generate his gauge it's really simple
when he does his fourth basic combo he
generates Ates mist and then when you
continue shooting at enemies through
this Mist he generates gauge points over
here so right now I have it full for
demonstration the next thing you do to
expand the gauge point is Dodge into the
Mist so like this and then
Dodge and release for his e skill it's
similar he places a decoy targets will
be baited to it and it also fires Miss
missiles from it and also generates a
miss so you can shoot through it as well
and Dodge into it as well so you press e
and then you start shooting get the full
gauge and then you dodge into it and
release that's how you play it in combat
all right so let's test it on crownless
same thing pistols cannot Parry so be
careful got the Miss shoot through the
Miss Dodge into it
release make Mist again Dodge into the
Mist release use e
skill generate Miss Dodge into it
release but that's generally how you
play Alto so for his ultimate he
generates a screen same thing you just
want to shoot through the screen and all
bullets get a damage increase so I'll
place it like this and then just shoot
through it can place your e as well
shoot through
it and do this even miss bullets that go
through the screen gets the damage
increase so yeah that's about it for
alto really simple
okay the favorite dungeon how to play
her she has two combos this combo that
is the mark combo and then this
combo that is her damaging combo like
the main combo that she uses so the
reason why you want to do the mark combo
is because she leaves a mark where she
does 20% more damage to them and it
lasts for 12 seconds so always have that
up she can also do the mark combo when
you press e after doing a Dodge counter
so let's start with the mark combo Mark
combo two base Bic and two e so two
basic two e that's the mark combo the
long combo same thing three basic three
e three basic 3
e you can also substitute the first
basic with an E it's the same thing so
like Mark combo e basic e e or the three
one e basic basic e e e so the more e
you use the more gauge you use like this
and then once she has at least half
gauge you can press and hold left click
and she'll do her nuke attack and then
press basic to finish it off so of
course you want it to do at maximum
gauge for the maximum amount of damage
you can also do it at half
gauge she gets some healing when she
does this like
that and also Ultimate Energy and also
her e skill has no cooldown it uses her
health that's something to know now
let's try it on
crownless I'm already pre-charging
placing the mark now you can see the
mark on him it's like a flower
symbol and Dodge counters can be done
with e as well let me
demonstrate Dodge and then basic and
then e so every time she Dodge counters
she renews The Mark with her Mark combo
and then press and hold left click and
left click
again that's how you play dungeon
ultimate is just a flurry of
attacks like
that in short two basic two e first for
the mark and then three basic three
e and then you can also substitute the
first basic before an
e or e basic basic e e e and then once
the gauge is half or full just hold left
click and left click
again that's it
okay so for yenu it's really easy all
you need to do is place the Thunder
witch which is his e skill place this
down and he'll continually charge his
gauge this thing here will also perform
support attack when he attacks the enemy
during this and once it's full press and
hold e and for 10 seconds he goes into
an enhanced State attacking even faster
comes with a new heavy
attack
that and also does more stagger damage
that's pretty Prett much it how to play
y u really simple Place e down full
gauge hold down e and just beat them up
so let's try it on
crownless
okay he is ready
and ultimate is a super punch that gives
10 seconds of anti-
interruption pull e again and beat the
hell out of
crownless and pretty much it that's how
you play
yenu this thunder wedge also stays on
the field when you switch characters
allowing them to get support attacks
from it as well like
that and that that's it moving on to the
next
character Mortal Fe also very simple
just press e on cool down and just keep
shooting them that's it just keep
shooting them and when you see e just
press it on cool down and when his
ultimate is ready you can activate it
and switch to the next character and
it'll perform support fire whenever they
do basic or heavy attacks so let's try
it same thing just keep shooting e on
cool down
and then alt and
switch look at all the support
fires all right moving on to the next
character all right time for the five
star starting with calaro calaro is
really simple all you need to do is
perform three e on the Target and he'll
get one gauge segment each so one two
and three and then you finish it off
with heavy attack by holding left click
that's all now let's go straight into
battle you can also chain the e in
between it has uh you have about 7
Seconds to perform the next e if it's
too hot second e I'm going to Parry this
third
e Parry this hold left
click that's his Forte attack so e e e
oh left click
that's pretty much it how you play
calaro now for his ultimate it's really
simple just press ultimate and spam
basic that's all Spam basic he'll just
go
crazy there we go that's it and now
there's a special thing about Kelo after
he uses his ultimate his next intro
attack will be enhanced very
cinematic now watch this I'm going to
switch Calo in and you'll see his
improved intro attack for using
ultimate very
cool all right that's the end for curo
moving on to the next character for
lingyang all you need to know is his e
skill has no cooldown because it's a
finisher to his combo so every three to
five basic you can finish it off with e
so this will look different in combat
and once the gauge is filled from doing
that you can press and whole heavy
attack and just Spam basic after that he
does an air combo you can also press e
after every second combo for more damage
and that's the end this is the end of
the
combo using his ultimate will result in
a nuke and also give him 50% glacio for
14 seconds and also a large amount of
gauge and his Forte gets extended his
midair Forte so let's try it on
crownless so 1 2 3 e e that's the
forward lunge 1 2 3 e 1 2 3 e so now
that our gauge is full let's do it again
go up so one 2 e and then finish it
off like that and 1 2 3 e again 2 3 e 1
2 3 e let's Parry this all right let's
use ultimate you'll see what I mean
large amount of gauge straight to full
go back up one 2 e 1 2 e 1 2 e and
finish that's how you play
lingy one more thing he can also go into
a chain of heavy attack by constantly
doing heavy and then basic heavy basic
heavy basic just something for you to
know like that down forward down down
basic heavy down basic and that's it
moving on to the next character all
right next up Verina she's a five star
healer support and a really good one at
that for her she gets her Gauge by doing
her e skill or her fifth attack combo on
the Target or her intro skill and then
to spend her gauge all you need to do is
either do her heavy the slight or Air
Attack like that so if you want to clear
it really quickly all you need to do is
just jump attack she can do it three
times like that and while spending the
gauge she gets healing and also contal
energy like that get gauge 1 2 3 4 5 use
e 1 two 3 4
5 already got that Parry
in and then I just need to jump and
attack let me Parry this jump attack one
two three three gauge can also slide
like that
and then as for her ultimate she will
place a mark on the enemy and then
anyone that attacks the target will get
healed and also spectral damage on them
so I'll do
ultimate switch
in so you see the plan roots are
attacking
crownless also with
healing and switch her back in again
look it's already ready coner ready so
she's really easy to play very user
friendly and that's it for Verina next
character okay now for Encore Encore
also gets her gauge from doing her e
skill basic attack and intro and also
her ultimate attack and then once her
gauge is full all you need to do is
press left click and she'll just explode
like this
[Music]
as for her e skill there is two parts to
it so you press e and then when you see
the prom you press e again like so e and
then e as for resonance Liberation her
ultimate all her moves will change so
you will start with E first and then
spam basic then e again and then spam
basic and then finish it off with charge
attack so let me demonstrate it to you
let me just dodge this okay okay e first
and then spam basic and then e again
once the cool down is up e again now
spam
basic e again
heavy so that's the special charge
attack only available during ultimate
and then we're back to normal form we
just use everything on cool down two
parts
e so it's really hard to Parry with
Encore during this form it's a lot
easier during ultimate so just be
careful she also takes reduced damage
during the charge
attack that's pretty much it that's how
you play
Encore okay and now for one of my most
favorite characters Jensen she attack
she protect she Shield she heals she
blocks so let's go straight into battle
and I'll show you what I mean her e
skill is a block like this and any
incoming attack she will negate all the
damage and perform a
counter and any attack will generate her
gauge and once it's full we'll see what
happens
okay let me Parry this once it's full
press and hold left
click and as it reaches the different
tiers she gains the gauge you can also
stop this at any time but if you let it
hold all the way she gains the biggest
shield and also gets healing for 30
seconds every second
seconds so in other words she can really
die if you constantly use her skills so
if I block it like
this there we
go I can't do it again so I can release
it
early like
that and her ultimate is a pull just
pulls everyone
in yeah this is tensen
okay let me block
this like that I can't even
uh just charge this ignore all of
Crown's
combo there we go full shield again
never killing
me
counter so it negates every damage with
our e skill all you need to do is just
hold e
that then charge
this that's it that is tensen she does
pretty much everything and now onto the
final
character so for G Yen his e skill is a
four thrust like
this and it gets further enhanced when
he has gauge so his gauge gain is really
simple just fight in combat and he'll
build the gauge his e skill can also be
used in the air like
this and that's about it that's all you
need to know his ultimate can be
triggered with and without gauge if he
uses his ultimate with no gauge it looks
like
this and then you just span basic attack
like that you can also use e skill
during this if you use e skill during
his ultimate it's considered enhanced as
if it has the
gauge and it ends with the final hit of
his normal combo so that's GN for you
pretty easy to use as long as he has
gauge just use e skill to enhance it so
let me demonstrate it to
you
that okay so look what
happens I'll use e skill and it uses
half a gauge for an enhanced
e e skill with Gauge again
okay what happens when I have full gauge
of ultimate let's find out you can also
activate this by jumping so he will
throw the spear instead and then go back
to this and use e on cool down then spam
basic and then use e on coold down again
when it's once it's
back e and then spam
basic and that's the end of it same
thing so the gist of GN you just want to
enhance his e skill and ultimate with at
least half a gaug when it's
ready that's pretty much his play style
and that's all 16 characters play style
summarized I hope this has been helpful
to you in understanding their play style
for launch and let me know in the
comments on what kind of guides you
would like to see in the future I also
stream withering waves so you can also
catch me on Twitch consider leaving a
comment like subscribe to the channel
and I'll see you in the next video
bye-bye